Olorun t'o da awon oke igbani
My God who created the ancient hills
Eyin ni mo fi ope mi fun
I give all my praises to You
Olorun t'o da awon oke igbani
My God who created the ancient hills
Eyin ni mo fi ope mi fun
I give all my praises to You
Lift your hands, Church, and say:
T'ani n'wo tun gbe ga o bi ko se Baba l'oke
Who else will I exalt if not You oh God
Tani n'wo tun fi gbogbo ope mi fun
Who else will I give my praises to
Olorun t'o da awon oke igbani
My God who created the ancient hills
Eyin ni mo fi ope mi fun
I give all my praises to You
Olorun t'o da awon oke igbani
My God who created the ancient hills
Eyin ni mo fi ope mi fun
I give all my praises to You
Olorun t'o da awon oke igbani
My God who created the ancient hills
Eyin ni mo fi ope mi fun
I give all my praises to You
T'ani n'wo tun gbe ga o bi ko se Baba l'oke
Who else will I exalt if not You oh God
Tani n'wo tun fi gbogbo ope mi fun
Who else will I give my praises to
Olorun t'o da awon oke igbani
My God who created the ancient hills
Eyin ni mo fi ope mi fun
I give all my praises to You
T'ani n'wo tun gbe ga o bi ko se Baba l'oke
Who else will I exalt if not You oh God
Tani n'wo tun fi gbogbo ope mi fun
Who else will I give my praises to
Olorun t'o da awon oke igbani
My God who created the ancient hills
Eyin ni mo fi ope mi fun
I give all my praises to You
Somebody give Him a shout!
For there is no one, except You, Jesus, in Heaven and on earth!
There is nobody!
Give it to Him!
Come on!
Hallelujah!
Olorun, You are the Maker of Heaven and earth!
There is nobody like You, Jesus!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How great You are
Lift your hands!
If you know that He is greater than anything today, lift your hands and say:
How great You are
It's so simple. Just open your lips and say, "How great You are, Jesus!"
You are so great to us, Jesus! We love You!
How great You are
You are so great to us, Jesus!
We worship You! We adore You, Jesus! You are so great!
How great You are
Agbanilagbatan
Great Deliverer
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Somebody scream!
Overflow Congregation
Agbanilagbatan
Great Deliverer
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you.
Hallelujah!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Good Morning, Church!
You may have your seat. Thank you.
Agbanilagbatan
Great Deliverer
That is the last word - Agbanilagbatan.
That is God for you. He is not a man.
Agbanilagbatan
Great Deliverer
That is God!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He is not a man.
When He says, "Yes", it is yes; no one can say, "No".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I want to salute our viewers all over the world for your time. Thank you very much.
Wherever you are, Jesus is there. The state of your heart matters; distance is not a barrier.
Are you there, my viewers?
Yes. Thank you.
God gave me a Word for you today.
That quickly leads me to the book of Psalm 66 which I'm going to read for you right now.
The book of Psalm 66.
"For you, God, tested us; you refined us like silver.
You brought us into prison and laid burdens on our backs.
You let people ride over our heads; we went through fire and water,
but you brought us to a place of abundance."
Listen to that again. Let me read that verse 12.
"You let people ride over our heads; we went through fire and water,
but you brought us to a place of abundance."
This means God refines us with affliction.
It means sin easily hides where there is no heat of trial and affliction,
just as impurities hide in gold unless it goes through the furnace.
Impurities will hide in gold.
I was trying to ask a gentleman in the church - I believe he will be in the church today -
after calling and calling, I said, "Can you trace this man inside the church?"
Later, I got to know that the man did not come to church today. I said, "Why?"
Because he has a knocked engine.
He got up in the morning and found out that the vehicle's engine knocked.
That should be the reason.
As if the God that gave the vehicle cannot withdraw the vehicle.
The God that gave the vehicle to you cannot as well withdraw it?
When He noticed what only He Himself knows -
nobody knows the reason; He can decide to withdraw what He has given you.
God Himself. That is God for you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When God noticed what only He has knowledge of - nobody knows the reason;
but He knows that if He allows this man to take this vehicle today,
something worse might happen to him.
So because of that, something will happen to the vehicle to preserve the man, to protect you.
To preserve him for the greater...
But because of this, our brother did not come to church.
He said, "Ah, the engine knocked".
"Hm, the engine knocked?"
That was the only reason given.
This is the manifestation of sin which hides where there is no heat of trial.
Manifestation of weakness.
When there is no heat of trial and temptation, you look so nice and gentle.
Very godly. It is too early to say, "Eh, this is a pastor, this is a bishop, this is a born-again".
"This is..." - whatever you call the name.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let the heat of trial come before you judge, before you say, "This is T.B. Joshua,
this is Prophet T.B. Joshua, this is a bishop".
Allow the heat of trial and temptation come. Then you can say that he is a bishop.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your fellow Christian brother there what he does not want to hear and hear the reaction.
"He is a born-again".
You know that he is a pastor or whoever - your neighbour inside the church.
Just tell him what he does not want to hear at all and see his reaction.
Let will tell you that he is a born-again.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Your weaknesses hide where there is no heat of trial and temptation.
Tell your neighbour.
Sin hides where there is no heat of trial and temptation.
You see a man, very nice and quiet.
"Hm, he is quiet."
Ok. Tell him what he does not want to hear and see his reaction.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Where there is no heat of trial and temptation, our weaknesses hide.
As if we are truly born-again.
Indeed, let temptation come.
Let someone lie against you. Let us see how you handle the situation.
Your response to offence matters - determines your future.
Your response to temptation, heat of trial, affliction determines your salvation.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Don't forget the case of Job.
Before satan went to Job, he first consulted the Almighty God to give him permission.
What are you going through?
Ask God to help you make the most of difficulties.
What is your situation?
They are not meant to destroy you.
It may be to refine you.
I want to tell you:
Oftentimes, God works through the circumstances of life.
Tell your neighbour.
I can't hear you.
Oftentimes, God works through the circumstances of life.
Because we don't know and it is difficult for us men of God to preach this -
because how do we preach it?
I listen every day, all the time, to this message but it is so difficult.
This is my personal experience.
Oftentimes, God works through the circumstances of life, your adverse circumstances
for the purpose of cleansing and separating us from unclean and impure elements
such as anger, bitterness, unforgiveness.
Overflow Congregation
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yes. Take this quote.
Oftentimes, God works through the circumstances of life.
You ask God all the time to help you to make the most of difficulties.
Help me as You did Joseph.
You know what Joseph went through before the palace, before the throne.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Potiphar's house - you know what happened.
Pit - you know what happened.
Ask Him, "Help me, Lord, as You did Joseph to make the most of difficulties".
Help me in my adverse circumstances to make the most of difficulties.
All these that make you cry, lament, depressed - they are there to preserve you.
It is time you should begin to see adverse circumstances as a friend, not enemy
because oftentimes, God works through the circumstances of life.
Your difficulty, sickness, disease, affliction, setback, attack.
Oftentimes, God works through them.
Are you with me?
Oftentimes, God works through them to take you to the throne.
He works through them.
Tell your neighbour:
Oftentimes, God works through my pain, affliction, setback - whatever you call it.
He works through them.
But when this comes, you lament, "Ah, this is the enemy! This is wahalla! This is trouble!
This is to destroy me!"
Time to be depressed, cry, lament, commit suicide.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you had not gone through that pain, who knows what would have happened to you.
If you had not been on the sickbed for a while, and you are out there,
going everywhere you want to go, who knows what would have happened to you.
If you had not run into debt at the time you run into debt,
who knows what would have happened to you if you had had the chance to move everywhere.
If you had got that pregnancy and had a baby,
who knows what would have happened to you whilst being in the pregnancy stage
or if you had that baby, who knows what would have happened.
If you had not been sacked from that place, who knows what would have happened.
Tell your neighbour.
Oftentimes, God works through the circumstances of life.
So it is now time for you to think about yourself.
Think about yourself.
"Ah! I was going from one witchdoctor to another because of this problem.
I never knew that God was working through it to take me to the throne!
I was looking at God in a very bad light!
'Ah, my God! What happened! Why did this happen?'
I never knew God was working things out for me through it."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So rise up right now and say after me with all your heart:
Lord, give me a greater understanding of Your heart.
I can't hear you.
Do you know the reason? Because Jesus is Lord over your life.
That is why you need greater understanding of His heart.
If I'm right? Jesus is Lord over your life.
Am I right?
I can't hear you.
Yes!
Who is Lord over your life?
Jesus!
Open your lips and say to the Lord, "Give me a greater understanding of Your heart
because Jesus is Lord over my life!"
"Because You are the Lord over my life,
give me a greater understanding of Your heart!"
Overflow Congregation
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In Jesus Christ's name we pray.
You know, if you ask many people here today, "What is your dream?"
They say, "No, I don't even understand whether I dream.
I don't even understand the word 'dream'".
And God gives dream to guide us for this life.
To guide you - it is for guiding.
He gives dream to guide us for this life.
Without dream, you will continue to walk in the dark, without direction.
People believe that they must sleep before they have a dream.
It is a thing of the heart.
Like you are standing now - dream is going on.
The thought of God - your heart is telling you, "Ho, yes, yes!"
This is why we are asking for a greater understanding of God's heart -
because Jesus is Lord over your life.
Ask God to help you to see the dream for you.
But not ask God for the dream - the dream is there already!
Some people will say, "Ok, ask for dream! Dream! I want to dream!"
No! Already! It is only that you are ignorant.
You can't understand the voice of God.
This is why I said to you that what you are going through,
is to separate you from (what is) unclean and impure such as bitterness, hatred.
A lot is going on in your heart.
Pain of the past, offence.
You need a greater understanding of God's heart to know that what you are going through,
God is aware.
God is working through your circumstances.
God is working through your sickness.
God is working through your affliction.
God is working through your setback.
You need a greater understanding of God's heart to understand this.
If not, you will continue to run to the witchdoctor, to join a secret cult because of your problem.
Run into this, run into that.
Making a covenant to the world.
Run into this and that because you don't understand.
You think this is a problem, this is satan to you
whereas oftentimes, God works through your circumstances of life.
See your dream, in the name of Jesus!
In the mighty name of Jesus, see your dream!
You people pray for dream. Don't pray for the dream; it is there already.
As you are created, you are created with a dream.
Dream means direction. This is direction but you can't see.
But for you to ask now for direction, God should give you that...
No! The direction is there already!
See your dream, in the name of Jesus!
What is my dream? How will I get there?
Our walking with the Lord - good and hard times alike.
You are walking with the Lord.
Hard - good.
Hard could be sickness, disease, setback, temptation, affliction.
Good - bad.
That is our walking with the Lord.
Oftentimes, he works through the circumstances of life.
Good - bad.
This is how you are built.
In the same vein, day - night.
When it is night, you have to sleep.
That is how you grow and become old; through day - night.
You become strong in the Lord through good and bad.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You just need a greater understanding of God's heart to understand this.
Our walking with the Lord - good and hard times alike.
A lot of hard time whilst you are sacrified.
But reward, a lot of good - there will be hard time but so much good.
But sacrify - the word 'sacrify' - reward.
Sacrify - a lot of hard time.
Not that there will be good but a lot of hard time.
And you are sacrified now.
You have not yet reached the reward time.
Forget about your age.
When you reach reward time, you will begin to eat with the Lord, see vision clear,
have a greater understanding of God's heart.
As I'm standing now, you will be able to ... oh my God!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
As I'm standing now, you will be able to know who is talking to you.
It is T.B. Joshua or Prophet T.B. Joshua.
But right now, I don't think anyone knows who is talking to him.
You only see a man standing, called T.B. Joshua. You don't know who is talking to you.
That is why it is difficult for you to believe, unless the mighty grace comes upon you.
You need faith to believe.
Tell your neighbour, "I need faith to believe. Give me faith to believe".
I can't hear you.
I need faith to believe. Give me faith to believe.
Who is going to give you faith?
God!
I need faith to believe. Give me faith to believe.
You need faith to believe. You don't just run into the church and say,
"They said I should come to the Synagogue today. Ok, I'm in the Synagogue.
I believe. I believe in what is happening here".
Oh, you believe? But you still need faith to believe.
Back again.
Dream is a gift of God.
Tell your neighbour.
Some people say, "I want to dream".
Pray, fast. Fast, pray.
It is a gift. Something that is a gift from God.
Not the work of righteousness which you have done but according to His grace you dream.
It is a gift from God, just as faith is a gift from God.
That is why you say, "I need faith.
You can manufacture your belief but faith cannot be (manufactured)
because you must have that faith in the finished work of God.
Not in yourself - you can decide to believe.
"I believe the man. I believe the business."
But the word faith cannot be used that way.
See your dream, in the name of Jesus!
There is no way we can see our dream when in hard times, we lament.
You run to the witchdoctor, lamenting.
You stop praying; you stop even coming to church.
If God that gave you a vehicle decided to withdraw it,
when He noticed what only Him understands, is it a crime?
The One that gave you can decide to withdraw it.
Can you see?
To test your faith, someone can just come to lie against you, to show your response -
those you kept inside.
To people, you are a man of God. To people, you are a born-again.
But let this temptation come and see how you react.
A lot of people have been in the court - you have sued them for this and that.
You never knew that God works through the circumstances of life.
That is why your response should be of God.
You can never hear me respond to any issue because I know how God works.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
See your dream, in the name of Jesus!
God gives dream to guide us in this life.
For this life, you need guidance.
"You will dream, dream, dream!" - that is the book of Joel.
But how many of you dream today?
Before even coming here, you are supposed to actually know what my appearance will be -
what kind of wears I will put on, and you will see it clearly.
By the time you see clear, you say, "Oh! This is actually what I saw it in the dream!"
to tell you, "Oh, yes. Today is your day!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is everywhere. It is with you.
It is for you. It is a gift.
You are born with it. Your dream is only dormant, unused - it is there.
So you take this message home today:
Oftentimes, God works through the circumstances of life.
Anytime you are having a challenge, think over it - the position of God - before you comment.
When someone lies against you, sit back.
Know the position of God before you comment.
When temptation comes, what is God's position?
All this divorce, divorce, divorce, everywhere broken home.
If you take time to know God's position, you will know that for 90% of this, God is aware.
God used this for a purpose - to preserve, to cleanse the house,
to separate them from unclean and impure.
See your dream, in the name of Jesus!
Because Jesus is Lord over your life, see your dream, in the name of Jesus!
When you see your dream, you know God's position concerning your affliction, burden,
God's position concerning what you are going through, challenges, situation, condition.
See your dream, in the name of Jesus!
You need to know God's position
because oftentimes, He works through the circumstances of life.
You know how He helped Joseph in adverse circumstances.
He helped Joseph. Look at the history of Joseph.
He was with Joseph, and you with God are majority.
See your dream, in the name of Jesus!
One thing we don't know about our enemy:
When they hit you, trying to attack you, and you are silent,
it creates fear to your enemy.
They will not know your position.
And they don't know what you mean by your silence.
But when you respond - they love response.
"Please, this is a secret!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour, "Your enemy loves your response. It gives them the next strategy to use.
When they kick you, shout at you, lie against you, and you come out to say,
"You lie against me!", they say, "Glory!". They are happy.
"He, we hit him! Hit him more!"
"He, he!"
"Oh, hit him more!"
The same way satan:
When you want to pray and you begin to say, "Satan, satan!",
satan will be happy. He always wants attention.
He want to hear the word 'satan' in your mouth.
He wants you to confess, talk about him.
When you don't talk about him, you just ignore him,
you are not even mentioning anything about him, it is always very painful to him.
Satan loves attention.
That is why I used to tell some of our members
when people are in a prayer mode and you now stand up, showing your shoes, stuff and all that,
I said they should help me in giving the names of people like that.
Satan is using them.
That is when they want to show off their stuff, attire, beauty,
you will see them moving around the church at a time people are quiet.
Satan likes attention.
When you ignore satan - you see me the way I ignore satan.
There is nothing you will say, unless God says, "Talk!"
When you just say something, I will be looking. I want to know God's position.
Even if God could not give me a response instantly, I'm always patient
because there is nothing I will gain in responding.
Because I depend on God's ability and power than man's majority.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God's authority is final.
You know, you need support...
So please, take note of that.
Your enemy loves your response.
That gives them next strategy and tactic to use.
When you don't respond, and they abuse, and curse you, whatever they say about you,
and you don't respond, that is the end of the matter.
Overflow Congregation
Yes, that is their end.
But that is not God's end. Where they stop, God starts.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So that is it.
From your response, they know how mighty, little, big you are.
When you talk, the enemy listens to your voice.
From your voice, they know the value of what you are saying.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yes. So take note of this from today.
Your enemy needs your response. That is why they attack you.
And when you are quiet, they don't know what you are doing.
They are afraid. Your silence is very dangerous.
They too know God. It is only that they don't believe.
So when you are quiet, they are afraid that "Hey, this man might be migthy in the spirit"
because they know that you are a spirit man.
Are you not a spirit man?
[Yes!]
Does the spirit talk?
[No!]
Eh hen.
So take this home today.
In summary, your enemy needs your response for attack.
To attack you next, they need your response.
So, take note.
When you don't respond, it means you have a big God who is fighting for you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Every response of your enemy, take it God - take it for prayer.
If your enemy says, "You are a thief", write it down, take it to your altar.
If your enemy says, "You are stupid", write it down, take it to your altar.
Don't use your mouth to reply. Take it to your altar.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
By the time you have written down all the response of your enemy -
"I will kill you; I will destroy you" - just write everything down with the date.
"They will kill you; they will destroy you" - write it down and take it to the altar of God and say,
"I am a spirit; I am only living in a physical body, learning to live in this physical world".
So, what else again?
Take it to the altar of God.
Two: Oftentimes, God works through the circumstances of life.
Your adverse circumstances.
Oftentimes, many times.
These adverse circumstances you see as an attack from the enemy, from this, from that -
mighty God is using them for cleansing; to separate you from unclean and impure elements.
That you are silent and quiet does not mean that you are a Christian.
Very gentle, wearing rag - it does not mean that you are a child of God.
Christisnity lies in the heart.
What does your heart say?
You may be seated. Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Give me a greater understanding of Your heart - that should be your prayer today.
That should be going on in your heart.
Give me a greater understanding of Your heart because Jesus is Lord over my life.
Because You are Lord over my life, give me a greater understanding of Your heart.
So, this is what you need now.
"Give me a greater understanding of Your heart" because you don't understand God's heart.
That is why when attack comes, you attack back, the same way.
And you never knew that oftentimes, the person that attacks you does not matter
but the position of God concerning the attack matters.
Tell your neighbour, "Oftentimes, the person that attacks me does not matter
but the position of God concerning that attack matters".
Yes, that is it.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If Judas was not sent to betray Jesus and Jesus was not crucified,
today, we would not talk of the Saviour.
The person that attacked me, oftentimes, does not matter.
When you just say, "Ah, you attacked me!" - I look at him.
He does not even matter; he is being used to take you to the throne.
Many a time, the attacker is being used to take you to the throne.
He does not matter; he is just being used.
He is a particle.
But the position of God concerning that attack matters.
"What is Your position, God, concerning this attack?"
"Oh yes, this position is to cleanse and preserve you for the new level!
It is to strengthen your desire and your determination for me, God!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, these are the things we need to know.
Please, don't waste your time over your enemy
because he uses the content of your words to strategise.
"I will deal with you!"
"Eh hen!"
He wants to see those behindg you.
Silence is the best answer for a fool.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Silence is the best answer for your enemy.
Write it down.
Silence is the best answer for my enemy.
Yes.
Nothing makes you better than your enemy when you respond.
Nothing makes me better than my enemy when I respond.
"You are an idiot!" - "You too are an idiot!"
What makes you better now?
Who is now an enemy?
The two of you.
The two of you are now an enemy of God.
"You are an idiot!" - "You too are an idiot!"
Who is now the Christian among you?
Nothing makes me better when I respond.
The attacker does not matter many times
but the position of God concerning the attack matters.
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Mel Flowers 29/06/2018